# Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

# **Android Developer**

@ hadilashkari@gmail.com

+98 939 125 8116

github.com/hadilq

stackoverflow.com/users/2482947 in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

#### **Summary**

A curious developer with over 14 years of experience in software development, where almost 4 years of his experience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student. An introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value driven and passionate developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, and

efficient apps to make the world better place to live.
A person whose goal is to surround himself with happy, creative, motivative and clever persons, so his talent hecomes flourished

He's interested in Data Science and Data Engineering so currently he's looking forward to learn TensorFlow Lite as soon as possible.

# **Experience**

## Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

🛗 Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

O Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions

#### Missions:

- Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.
- As functional manager of the Android team, he was responsible for the code quality of the Sheypoor app. He coached the team to practice design patterns, clean code, and using app architecture, along with updating libraries and adding new features with focus on agility and UX.
- Implementing new design of the entire app, including rebranding for summer campaign.
- · Improving the legacy code quality by adding Dagger and Kotlin.

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao, etc.
- · Agile, Kanban, Git Flow. CI/CD
- Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco
- Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, etc.

#### Senior Android Developer

m Sep. 2015 - Des. 2017

O Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users.

- Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.
- Implementing features such as handling deeplinks, search page, inbox page, etc.

### **Technologies**:

- Volley, OneSignal, EventBus, OrmLite, etc.
- · Agile, Scrum, Git Flow
- · Mockito, Espresso
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jfrog, Jenkins

#### Java and C# developer

at Soha System

m Mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

O Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards.

#### Missions:

- · Implementing RFID card reader Android app via bluetooth connection.
- Implementing Android and desktop apps.

#### Lecturer

at Universities

m Feb. 2012 - Dec. 2014

Mashhad, Iran

After two years of enrollment by conscription, he had been working in two universities, Payame Noor University and Sadjad University of Technology.

# Courses Taught:

· Application of Computers in Physics, Mathematical Physics, etc.

#### **Article**

ProAndroidDev post: Logging in Kotlin
ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern

ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events

# **Education**

Sharif University Of Technology Payame Noor University

in Physics in Physics

Feb. 2010 ∰ Jul. 2007

Tehran

Mashhad

## **Tools / Skills**

Android Architecture Components/JetPack Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging ViewModel/WorkManager Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/. Butter Knife/ObjectBox/..

#### Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture MVVM, MVP, RMVVM

### Principle

Clean Code/SOLID Object Oriented Programming Functional Programming
Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

# Design Pattern

Factory/Builder/Singleton/.. Adapter/Facade/Proxy/. Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

#### Android test library

JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

#### **Build Tool**

Gradle/Maven/Ant/Make/...

# Command Line Tool

grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/. adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

### Development Tool

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/...

# **Programing Language**

Java/Kotlin/Scala/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Rust/...

### Operating System

Linux(Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

# Special Honor

- Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in Physics at Spring 2007.
- Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor

# Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume in github Built at February 27, 2019